<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-02T20:42:53-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Karl’s Personal Page</title><subtitle>An array of Interests</subtitle><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><entry><title type="html">Large-scale Cluster Management at Google with Borg</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research-papers/research/borg/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Large-scale Cluster Management at Google with Borg" /><published>2020-02-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-02-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research-papers/research/borg</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research-papers/research/borg/">&lt;p&gt;This paper provides a high-level overview of Google’s cluster manager: Borg. The paper describes the data warehouse environment, Borg’s architecture, and discusses performance related choices in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;googles-datacenter-environment&quot;&gt;Google’s Datacenter Environment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services and user work is submitted to Google clusters via notion of “jobs”, which consistent of one or more tasks which all run the same binary. Jobs are assigned an integer priority level within non-overlapping bands. The lowest priority of jobs are &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;best effort&lt;/code&gt;, followed by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;batch&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;production&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;monitoring&lt;/code&gt;. Each task within a job has an associated set of both hard and soft constraints, mainly relating to resources such as CPU cores, memory requirements, disk space, disk I/O rate, and network I/O. All jobs (and machines) are monitored and suppored by a web-used user interface to track jobs, cells, and tasks, similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.14778/1920841.1920886&quot;&gt;Dremel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;architecture&quot;&gt;Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/papers/borg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Borg Architecture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the highest level, Borg is decomposed into cells. Cells are essentially clusters of about 10K machines, and may be hetergenous. Each cell maintains a “Borgmaster” which consists of a main process and scheduler process which is replicated for reliability. The scheduler operates in a round robin fashion within priority bands. Machine assignment operates similar to [Sparrow], but checks a variable number machines, computing scores for equivalence classes. Jobs are then scheduled based on their cached eqivalence class score. For a 10,000 machine cell, a Borgmaster still fits inside a single node comfortably. Interestingly, best-fit packing can be suboptimal as a misprediction can result in the need for preemption. Nevertheless, Borg supports preemption of lower priority tasks for higher priority tasks. At the machine level, a “Borglet” maintains monitor the machine and current tasks, as well as provides a heartbeat to the Borg master. The smallest unit in the architecture is an &lt;em&gt;alloc&lt;/em&gt;, a reserved set of resources for one ot more tasks, and can be grouped across machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;performance-analysis&quot;&gt;Performance Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper covers some specifics on design choices and the respective impacts on performance, I won’t conver all of them in detail. The first experiment aims at understanding the efficiency. The problem is analyzed through the lens of answering the question: could we remove machines and still maintain the performance? Their CDF shows about to achieve 90% confidence, there is only about 5% overhead. Secondly, cells are shared between &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;prod&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;non-prod&lt;/code&gt; workloads which results in better resource utilization. In fact, diverse applications generally led to better CPI. To ensure priority levels and job resources are enforced, Borg tasks run inside a Linux cgroup-based container. This allows the OS to control CPU and memory use for individual tasks. Note that soft interfence (memory bandwidth, cache pollution) is not accounted for. When tasks exceed their &lt;em&gt;non-compressable resources&lt;/em&gt; (e.g. memory use), they must be killed, whereas &lt;em&gt;compressible resouces&lt;/em&gt; (e.g. disk I/O rate) can be controlled via time multiplexing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-insights&quot;&gt;Key Insights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small units of abstraction, such as &lt;em&gt;allocs&lt;/em&gt; are useful for tracking and managing resources and tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Significant investment is monitoring and analysis is critical. Note that monitor jobs have a higher priority and production tasks!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A cluster manager is in many ways equivalent to the kernel of an OS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cluster management is holistic: it includes managing task lifecycles, guaranteeing availability, naming, loading balancing and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future readings in the Space:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usenix.org/conference/osdi14/technical-sessions/presentation/boutin&quot;&gt;Apollo&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft’s cluster manager. Includes per-job schedulers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eprints.whiterose.ac.uk/91136/&quot;&gt;Fuxi&lt;/a&gt;, Alibab’s cluster manager. Uses a resource offering scheduling technique.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.fb.com/data-center-engineering/tupperware/&quot;&gt;Tupperware&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook’s container scheduling service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><category term="Cluster management" /><category term="borg" /><category term="scale" /><category term="datacenter" /><category term="datawarehouse" /><summary type="html">This paper provides a high-level overview of Google’s cluster manager: Borg. The paper describes the data warehouse environment, Borg’s architecture, and discusses performance related choices in more detail.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 5 Recap, 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/weekly-recap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 5 Recap, 2020" /><published>2020-02-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-02-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/weekly-recap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/weekly-recap/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;metrics-tracking&quot;&gt;Metrics Tracking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going to track time and some other hard metrics. We’ll see how many I keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;This Week&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Last Week&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Work &lt;br /&gt; &amp;gt; Research &lt;br /&gt; &amp;gt; Reading &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;44 hr, 33 min &lt;br /&gt; 41 hr, 57 min &lt;br /&gt; 2 hr, 35 min&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;34 hr, 51 min &lt;br /&gt; Untracked &lt;br /&gt; untracked&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+ 9.7 hours&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reading&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0 hr, 8 min&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Untracked&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Underestimated…&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Writing&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;39 min&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Untracked&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I don’t include paper summaries here.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Papers&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Annual Total: 4&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Posts&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Annual Total: 11&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Gym&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Annual Total: 11&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;LoC&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1695&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Untracked&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(&lt;span style=&quot;color:green&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;+1388&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-307&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;!--
LOC: git log --since=2020-01-26 --shortstat --oneline
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notable-accomplishments&quot;&gt;Notable Accomplishments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submitted Paper to Conference&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applied for Graduation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Back to the gym!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Successful reading club presentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-defense meeting with a committee member - 2 more to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-worked-well&quot;&gt;What Worked Well?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week was a cluster f@$&amp;amp;!&lt;/em&gt; I think I realized that fully by Wednesay. As a result, 
I more or less treated like Tuesday/Wednesday as my “working weekend”, and told
myself I’d put in full-time days on the weekend. And I did! I realized the state
of affairs and made a decision. While at the time it felt like procastination, it was a
good trade off. My daily to-do list were long, but of mostly shorter tasks. This is
a list of what I had going on this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paper re-write for resubmission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduation logistics (actually confusing as hell)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scheduling meetings with 3 professors for my PhD proposal reviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preparing for those meetings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reading and presenting a paper for arch reading club&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RiTC Workshop website logistics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RiTC Workshop registration??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, way to much to make any real progress on my main research…&lt;strong&gt;until the
weekend.&lt;/strong&gt; I came in to the lab both Saturday in Sunday and wrote about 1000 lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-needs-improvement&quot;&gt;What Needs Improvement?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As easy as it is to justify the craziness, I’d be lying if I didn’t admit some things
slipped through the cracks. For instance, I wasn’t able to secure a sponsorship for traveling
to HPCA, so I wanted to check in with Rajeev before registering. Normally, he is
always in attendance at reading club, which was coincidentally also the last day
of early registration. Unfortunately, he wasn’t able to make it, and I totally 
spaced on following up – oof. Explainable, yes. Acceptable, no. If I do go to HPCA,
I’ll fork over my own money for the registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other major thing that I should touch on is momentum. I find between 4-6 hours into
a day, my productivity tanks. Like seriously. Hours one and two I’m at like 110%. Hours three and four, 85-90%. Hour 5 boom. 50%. Either that or I take a pause to eat lunch or something, and I lose my momentum completely. My initial thought was to get up and move around – and I think that’s right – but, where you move is critical. For instance, if you’ve lost your momentum then come home you’re going to cave into entertainment. I think moving around, walking, and then maybe moving to an alternate productive environment is the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, today after about 5 hours of coding, I enjoyed a 15 minute walk through crisp winter air to the library. I setup in my favorite corner, surrounded by the wonderful musty smell of old books, and 
got to reading a paper. After an hour of active  reading, I felt like I had digested a really complex paper and wrote a summary I’m happy with. So yes, moving in itself is good, but perhaps more importantly, moving to a space which fosters productivity is even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-could-make-you-happier&quot;&gt;What could make you happier?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy the time and metrics tracking, but I want to streamline it. While
the time tracking is pretty quick (I do it all with an app), the other metrics
aren’t streamlined yet and take a bit longer to compile. Would be nice to do that
quicker without feeling like I’m wasting time compiling extraneous information…
what can I say, I love data?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-next-week&quot;&gt;Goals for Next Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make Lyndsey’s 25th birthday awesome&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hit the gym at least once&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End-to-end reinforcement learning on real system implementation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start paper and nail down the story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read 2 papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strategies&quot;&gt;Strategies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;February strategy: No phone for the first 15 minutes of every day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep applying pomodoro technique through the coding grind&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experiment with changing the environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><summary type="html">Metrics Tracking</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">January 2020 Recap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/january-recap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="January 2020 Recap" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/january-recap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/january-recap/">&lt;p&gt;Well, since I’m wrapping up weeks, I might as well wrap up months too, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-tracking&quot;&gt;Time Tracking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is going to be a bit messy since I’ve only recently started being more
diligent, so bear in mind – a lot of missing hours!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Research&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;106 hr, 18 min&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Makes sense, did a lot of work on the car.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reading&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0 hr, 0 min&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Didn’t really track this separately.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Writing&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4 hr, 0 min&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Underestimated, without a doubt.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Social Media&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;22 hr, 15 min&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Underestimated… massively lol.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notable-accomplishments&quot;&gt;Notable Accomplishments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished S2000 winter prep&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Successful S2000 track day!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resubmitted Paper which was rejected&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applied for Graduation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Built this website!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-worked-well&quot;&gt;What Worked Well?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, it has been awesome to get time to work on my car. It’s my longest standing
passion in life (thanks Apa), bar none. Being in the garage was just so theraputic. 
You pour literal blood, sweat, and tears into a project and at the end your can
actually see what you did. You can experience what you did. And in the words of
David, the car is “sensory overload”, exactly what you need to clear a head as
inflated as mine. Hey at least I’m self-aware about my self-admiration, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xMxvO0xbQAo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting back to the grind started out alright. For one, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulletjournal.com/pages/learn&quot;&gt;bullet journal&lt;/a&gt; 
technique has been awesome. It’s nice to have a daily to-do list notebook, but,
one that’s a bit more structured. I definitely feel it adding value. In fact,
as a general prinicple I feel structure is the key ingredient for productivy, 
but paradoxically, chaos is the key incredient for inspiration and motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-needs-improvement&quot;&gt;What Needs Improvement?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s a balance. I seem to either spending too much time planning things
out too intricately on the larger scale, but then whip together an unrealistic
or unthoughtful daily todo list. Balancing having a good structure, yet having flexibility
when things don’t go to plan. And I’m thinking, the antitode to this? A balanced strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of action, I’m looking forward to getting into a morning routine. For 
one, I bought an alarm clock because I have a very simple goal: to start the day
for the first 15 minutes without my phone. I’m going to attempt to do this every
day in February. I’ve given it a few test drives, and I haven’t had a bad
day that starts without my phone. This is one clear change I’ll be making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, this action must be met with reflection to evaluate how well strategies
are working. Looking back on the past month (like I am now), is very subjective
in many ways. It gives a chance to take a high level view and see what’s missing,
or equally, what needs to be removed from my life. One key thing I learned is, 
when you have a good block of time to simply grind something out, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://francescocirillo.com/pages/pomodoro-technique&quot;&gt;Pomodoro technique&lt;/a&gt; 
is great. But if you have a day scattered with meetings, or a lot of 
small tasks to knock out – it’s not well suited for that. For instance, I considered
setting a goal “2 pomodoro sessions a day”, but it’s simply not realistic because
the type of work I do is so varied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-could-make-you-happier&quot;&gt;What could make you happier?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is the hardest one to answer, because what I truly desire is to change
the reality I’m in. I’m finishing up this PhD, but I want so badly to be done 
and to start working. I want to be back at Facebook, loving my job everday and
working with awesome people, in a concentrated team. I want to sleep next to my
wife every night, not a few times a month. I want to go track or wrench on my car every weekend.
I’m working towards this as absolute best as possible, but what could make me 
happier now? Maximizing my confidence that future I just described becomes reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strategies-for-next-month&quot;&gt;Strategies for Next Month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No cellphone use for the first 15 minutes of every day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear daily goal setting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consistent weekly recaps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-next-month&quot;&gt;Goals for Next Month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gym minimum once per week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish committee proposal review meetings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule defense&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Catch up my reading (1 paper per week)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><summary type="html">Well, since I’m wrapping up weeks, I might as well wrap up months too, right?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accelerating Distributed Reinforcement Learning with In-Switch Computing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research-papers/research/iswitch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accelerating Distributed Reinforcement Learning with In-Switch Computing" /><published>2020-01-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research-papers/research/iswitch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research-papers/research/iswitch/">&lt;p&gt;Venue:  ISCA 2019
Authors: Youjie Li, Iou-Jen Li, Yifan Yuan, Deming Chen, Alexander Schwing, Jian Huang&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper presents iSwitch, an in-switch accelerator which improves the performance of distributed machine learning training – specifically reinforcement learning. While reinforcement learning (RL) models are typically small compared to other DNN applications, they require significantly more training epochs to achieve convergence. As such, distributed training typically suffers from high communication costs because of frequent gradient aggregation and model updates. As such, the authors utilize a NetFPGA board to implement gradient aggregation within the switch itself, significantly reducing both communication and latency. Results are demonstated in for both synchronous and asychronous gradient updates, as well as with two baselines: a central parameter server (PS) and AllReduce-based training (AR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latency improves because gradient aggregation can happen as soon as gradients arrive at the switch. This happens asynchronously since environments, episodes, and overall experimental noise cause slight difference in gradient arrival time. The latency improvement also means that in the asynchronous scenario, training converges faster compared to the baseline since models are not so out of date with each other. Additionally, iSwitch is implemented such that gradient updates happen on each individual worker node, rather than at a centralized parameter server. Again, since communication is the dominant factor, it’s worth duplicating this work on individual worker nodes rather than performing the communication. Note that without gradient aggregation at the switch, you can’t perform worker level model updates with having a separate method for aggregation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3307650.3322259&quot;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;
 / &lt;a href=&quot;https://yifanyuan3.github.io/files/iswitch.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personal take:&lt;/em&gt; To the best of my knowledge, this is the first paper which proposes a switch-level optimization to improve machine learning training. However, the first paper to propose asynchronous gradient updates for RL (see my &lt;a href=&quot;https://karltaht.github.io/research-papers/research/a3c/&quot;&gt;A3C Post&lt;/a&gt;) mentions the key benefit is that all of this can be done a single machine, eliminating the majority of communication costs. In essense, state-of-the-art RL isn’t trained in a distributed fashion because 1) the models are small enough and 2) the communication is the bottleneck, so keeping everything on one machine is bonus. So while it’s clear the authors chose reinforcement learning because of it’s unique bottleneck of communication overheads, but I think this paper is equally important for scaling distributed training, just that RL was chosen because the benefits are more significant than other ML applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><category term="distributed machine learning" /><category term="reinforcement learning" /><category term="in-switch accelerator" /><summary type="html">Venue: ISCA 2019 Authors: Youjie Li, Iou-Jen Li, Yifan Yuan, Deming Chen, Alexander Schwing, Jian Huang</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reinforcement Learning Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/phd/reinforcement-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reinforcement Learning Resources" /><published>2020-01-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phd/reinforcement-learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/phd/reinforcement-learning/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/class/psych209/Readings/SuttonBartoIPRLBook2ndEd.pdf&quot;&gt;Reinforcement Learning: An Introduction (Sutton and Barto)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lectures&quot;&gt;Lectures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stanford, Lecture 14: Reinforcement Learning
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Great overview of all RL basics, closely follows Sutton and Barto’s text&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lvoHnicueoE&quot;&gt;Lecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cs231n.stanford.edu/slides/2017/cs231n_2017_lecture14.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hill-a/stable-baselines&quot;&gt;Stable Baselines&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is my personal favorite respitory for RL algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stable-baselines.readthedocs.io/en/master/&quot;&gt;Documentation available&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rlcode/reinforcement-learning&quot;&gt;Practical Implementions of OpenAI Gym Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><summary type="html">Books Reinforcement Learning: An Introduction (Sutton and Barto)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 4 Recap, 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/weekly-recap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 4 Recap, 2020" /><published>2020-01-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/weekly-recap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/weekly-recap/">&lt;p&gt;This is going to the first of what I hope are many “weekly recaps”. Think of it
as kind of hybrid between a personal sprint (see: ) and freeform journaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-tracking&quot;&gt;Time Tracking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; Monday was holiday, and we were moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Research&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;34 hr, 51 min&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reading&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0 hr, 0 min&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Writing&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Untracked&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notable-accomplishments&quot;&gt;Notable Accomplishments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implemented Reinforcement Learning Synthetic environment using A2C framework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moved back SLC and am setup for maximum attack!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Logistical graduation requirements squared&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paper Registered for ICS 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-worked-well&quot;&gt;What Worked Well?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s definitely nice being back in the lab and having a place to go work,
particularly when my wife is around. When I work from home and she leaves from
work, it kind of feels like I’m still just at home and not in “work mode”. Having
an office to go to when she’s around is definitely needed to keep that focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-needs-improvement&quot;&gt;What Needs Improvement?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sloppy with some of my bullet journal tasks, and as a result a lot of stuff
either didn’t get done or was migrated. My goals need to be a little bit more
well thought through. If the goal is to setup a framework but it’s not clear what
the requirements are, the task should be setting up the requirements. More tasks
can always be added as they arise, rather than trying to make up stuff. Also need 
to be honest about the to-do list for this paper submission. The biggest “oof”
this week was missing a time sensitive email by a full 24 hours. Felt bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-could-make-you-happier&quot;&gt;What could make you happier?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two main things bring me down: missing something critical and feeling like there’s
no time for fun. Organization is going to be key to make sure things don’t slip
through the cracks and bite me. Staying focused will help me ensure there IS
time to enjoy life, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-next-week&quot;&gt;Goals for Next Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take care when making daily goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finalize PhD committee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish revisions for ICS submission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start writing MICRO submission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Detailed Goal list for MICRO submission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measurements for simulation parameters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Progress on simulation environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><summary type="html">This is going to the first of what I hope are many “weekly recaps”. Think of it as kind of hybrid between a personal sprint (see: ) and freeform journaling.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Five Axioms for Productivity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/11_rules/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five Axioms for Productivity" /><published>2020-01-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/11_rules</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/11_rules/">&lt;p&gt;If you’re anything like me, you often find yourself reading or learning about
new techniques to improve yourself and your life. I think when you come across
these ideas they seem new and fresh and at face value always make a lot of sense.
The problem is that if you follow something like the self-improvement section on
Medium, you’ll be getting doses of new and fresh ideas everyday. One one hand,
this is really good. Things that are new keep us energized and excited to work
on ourselves. On the other hand, it really muddies the field in terms of what is 
important and what’s not. What really works versus what’s just interesting to 
consider. However, there’s one article that summarized some “Rules to Live By”
if you will, that I think are very powerful. I’m going to present them with my
own spin, and try to order it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-do-the-most-important-thing-first&quot;&gt;1. Do the most important thing FIRST.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each day, you choose the &lt;strong&gt;order&lt;/strong&gt; of when to do the things you need to do. Whether that’s taking
a shower and then having coffee, or grinding out an intensive task before checking
your email.  For me as a PhD student no longer taking classes, I have a ton of freedom in this. 
If I want to wake up at 1pm, spend the afternoon surfing YouTube, and start work
at 6pm, I theoretically have nothing stopping me on most days. However, I think
just reading that it’s pretty obvious that would be a terrible idea, but–why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I personally don’t think there’s a concrete answer. But, I do feel strongly 
that once you reward yourself with something, you feel accomplished. You’re less
incentivized to continue to work. Whether than be going straight to a reward
(e.g. waking up and watching Netflix) or, doing a small task and feeling like
you’ve made progress on your day (e.g. sending that email when you really need
to code up a new algorithm).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The reality is, your day is defined by the most important thing you accomplish.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-dont-multi-task&quot;&gt;2. Don’t multi-task&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People think that multi-tasking somehow improves our efficiency. It doesn’t. Have
you ever tried to scroll through Facebook while on the phone? You either missed
the conversation or you didn’t really read that post. People can’t think about
two things simulatenously. This is why I love the Pomodoro technique and wrote
and article dedicated to it. The whole point is you pick &lt;strong&gt;precisely&lt;/strong&gt; what you’re
going to focus on and do just that, no distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-own-your-time&quot;&gt;3. Own your time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like a lot of people have this mentality that hours in = progress out. In
reality, hours in &lt;strong&gt;times&lt;/strong&gt; intensity &lt;strong&gt;times&lt;/strong&gt; meaningfulness = progress out. When
we grind for too long, we lose focus both on what we’re doing and how we’re doing it.
This means you can’t just commit hours to something, you have to own those hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s three main points for point number 3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spending-at-least-50-of-your-time-doing&quot;&gt;Spending at least 50% of your time doing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you objectively look at your time, you probably spend a lot of time doing, well,
not productive things. Or at least, not directly productive things. Meetings, emails,
conversations, they are all necessary for progress and well being. But to truly
make an impact, you have to create. You have to do. Analyze your time and DO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-yourself-time&quot;&gt;Give yourself time.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as productive time matters, so does recharge time. During the day, this
means taking a lunch break to take a step back from work. Make sure your focused
and energized and ready for the afternoon. This also means scheduling – and I 
really mean scheduling – time to do stuff you just LIKE. Stuff that doesn’t
add toward self-improvement, but just self-happiness. It could be Netflix and Chill,
videos games, taking a drive. Whatever it is, make time for you to be happy. If
you’re not enjoying this thing called life, there’s really no point anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;track-your-time&quot;&gt;Track your time.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to really know much you’re working? How much Netflix you watch? Get a time
tracking app. There’s a lot of them out there, but I personally use “aTimeLogger”
which is super simple. You simple open the app and tap it when you start doing 
stuff. Be wary not to add too many categories or try to account for every minute
of the day. Instead figure out precise things that will help you answer questions
as to how you can better allocate your time. Maybe 20 hours of Netflix should be 
15 hours of Netflix and 5 hours of reading. Maybe the reason your so drained is
because you’re spending 60 hours at work and another 10 commuting. And don’t think
you have to dedicate a lot of retrospection to it either. Most days I just use it
to see, hey, have I really put in enough hours today? If not, how’s the week looking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, proceed with caution here. It’s easy to get sucked into a vortex of trying
to one-up yourself on how much time your spending on the things you “should be
spending time on”. While hours in are likely to improve your success, they’re
no guarantee of results. That’s why owning your time is 3, and doing what matters
most is first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-write-it-down--on-paper&quot;&gt;4. Write it down – on Paper.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I love typing and am a bit of a keyboard fanatic, I think there will always
be something borderline cerebral about physically writing with pen (or pencil) and
paper. Physically writing a check mark when you finish a pomodoro session or crossing
out an item on your to-do list. Besides that, the reality is we have shitty memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Physically writing things down helps us remember. It puts things in perspective. 
When you write down a to-do list of what you’re going to do today and its 20 items
long, you physically realize it’s too much. Now 20 is arbitrary, but if you’ll
start doing this everyday you’ll realize what you can realistically accomplish in
one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of late, I like the bullet journal technique. I use it because it’s great way
to track short, medium, and long term goals. More than that, it’s flexible. You
can add sections that are relevant to you. Mine personally has a “Papers Read” 
section as well as “Things I love about my PhD” section. You can also track goals
easily and more. I highly recommending looking into it as it really took my 
existing journaling technique to the next level, and I’m really happy with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-discipline&quot;&gt;5. Discipline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the last piece of the puzzle is grit. You have to really want to 
improve yourself, and want it as often and as hard as possible. Believe in yourself,
and invest in yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><summary type="html">If you’re anything like me, you often find yourself reading or learning about new techniques to improve yourself and your life. I think when you come across these ideas they seem new and fresh and at face value always make a lot of sense. The problem is that if you follow something like the self-improvement section on Medium, you’ll be getting doses of new and fresh ideas everyday. One one hand, this is really good. Things that are new keep us energized and excited to work on ourselves. On the other hand, it really muddies the field in terms of what is important and what’s not. What really works versus what’s just interesting to consider. However, there’s one article that summarized some “Rules to Live By” if you will, that I think are very powerful. I’m going to present them with my own spin, and try to order it as well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Asynchronous Methods for Deep Reinforcement Learning (A3C)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research-papers/research/a3c/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Asynchronous Methods for Deep Reinforcement Learning (A3C)" /><published>2020-01-16T09:57:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-16T09:57:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research-papers/research/a3c</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research-papers/research/a3c/">&lt;p&gt;This paper presents a framework to perform asynchronous gradient descent for 
optimization of deep nerual networks in the scope of reinforcement learning
problems. Most importantly, this work presents the asynchronous advantage 
actor-critic framework (A3C), which is currently one of the state-of-the-art
frameworks for deep reinforcement learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While neural networks are powerful universal function approximators making them
conceptually ideal for approximate reinforcement learning, they suffer from 
an inherit problem of instability and variance making convergence difficult to
achieve. As such, reinforcement learning has traditionally focused on off-policy
learning algorithms which were able to aggregate sufficient data during update
phases. However, this work changes that by providing a framework which reduces
resource requirements (for storing gradients) while maintaining reliability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The framework centralizes models on a single machine, reducing communication 
costs. Gradient descent can be done in a similar fashion to &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.nips.cc/paper/4390-hogwild-a-lock-free-approach-to-parallelizing-stochastic-gradient-descent.pdf&quot;&gt;Hogwild!&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike
previous works, each simulated environment runs with different exploration policies
and different environments. Since the updates occur online, this reduces the 
likelihood that two parallel learners will have the same bias. The result
is a technique which can be applied to a variety of RL algorithms (one-step SARSA,
n-step Q-Learning, and advantage actor-critic). As a general approach toward
solving RL problems, A3C seems to be one of the most successful in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-a3c-algorithm&quot;&gt;The A3C Algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/a3c_alg.png&quot; alt=&quot;A3C Algorithm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><category term="Reinforcement Learning" /><category term="RL" /><category term="A3C" /><summary type="html">This paper presents a framework to perform asynchronous gradient descent for optimization of deep nerual networks in the scope of reinforcement learning problems. Most importantly, this work presents the asynchronous advantage actor-critic framework (A3C), which is currently one of the state-of-the-art frameworks for deep reinforcement learning.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Flow and the Pomodoro Study Technique</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/pomodoro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flow and the Pomodoro Study Technique" /><published>2020-01-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/pomodoro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/pomodoro/">&lt;p&gt;One thing about studying, or really, any kind of working that has limited human
interaction faces one key challenge: staying focused. I think that’s true now 
more than ever with cell phones, social media, email. Everything is trying to 
pull us away from what we’re working on right now. We can make to-do list’s and
stay organized, but eventually we will have to sit down and simply use our mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing is – don’t discredit your to-lists and organizations. I keep
a journal, more specifically, a bullet journal, to track all my daily, monthly,
and longer term goals. Once you have these tasks distilled to a reasonable level,
you at least know where you focus &lt;strong&gt;should&lt;/strong&gt; be, and that’s step one. Now, how
do you force yourself to focus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flow&quot;&gt;Flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/flow.png&quot; alt=&quot;Challenge vs Ability&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s this really interesting chart that demonstrates this notion of “flow”, 
when we are focused on what we are doing and happy, and by extension, most 
productive. In reality, its really hard to achieve this state. Maybe your 
current projectis boring because it’s too easy. Maybe it’s intimidating and 
even starting stresses you out. So, is there a way we can force ourselves into
flow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pomodoro-technique&quot;&gt;The Pomodoro Technique&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pomodoro techinque is exceedingly simple, and involves disecting time into
manageable increments. You’ll work in 25-minute “sprints” with short breaks, and
after 4 of these sprints, you’ll take a longer break. Let’s lay it out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the task you want to work on. If you have your to-do list, this should
be easy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set a 25-minute timer. Eliminate all disractions and dive into the task at 
hand, and nothing else. No checking Facebook, emails, messages, etc. You work
until the timer goes off. The Pomodoro begins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physically WRITE a check-mark down on the paper. You’ve completed a Pomodoro.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a short break for 3-5 minutes. Grab yourself a drink, check those IMs. 
Do something NOT work related.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every 4 pomodoros, take a longer break like 20-30 minutes. I call a group
of 4 pomodoros a “pomodoro session”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what I love about this technique is how simple it is. One of my “to-do”
items every day now includes “Pomodoro Sessions x …” based on how much time I 
think I have to work that day. Now I’ll be honest, sessions 1 and 2 usually go
really well for me, but the 3rd session is usually a significantly harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, I used this technique a lot in early 2019 when I first started
working completely from home, and had a good amount of success. I completely
forgot about it however, after returning from my internship. I only recently 
recalled and it put it back to use, and I’m really pleased with the results. 
Time to hit 2020 running!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><summary type="html">One thing about studying, or really, any kind of working that has limited human interaction faces one key challenge: staying focused. I think that’s true now more than ever with cell phones, social media, email. Everything is trying to pull us away from what we’re working on right now. We can make to-do list’s and stay organized, but eventually we will have to sit down and simply use our mind.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paper Rejection Reflection</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/rejected/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper Rejection Reflection" /><published>2020-01-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/rejected</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reality/phd/rejected/">&lt;p&gt;Today, I found out my submission to the ISPASS conference was rejected. The
strange thing about it is, I mostly just feel confused. How should you really 
feel when a your work is rejected? Discredited? Angry? Confused? For me, I just
feel blank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, at the University of Utah in the Computer Science department, PhD 
candidates are expected to output at least 3 top-tier publications before defending
and graduating. In reality, that translates to something like 5-10 submissions
of varying caliber throughout the program. While I think I’ve submitted something
like 5 works, this submission was my 2nd &lt;strong&gt;major&lt;/strong&gt; work, in that, I really 
wanted/needed it to get accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The odd thing is, the rejection felt expected. Objectively, I defend the paper. 
I think it should have gotten in. It had novelty. It had results. It was cohesive. 
But in the end the results weren’t good &lt;strong&gt;enough&lt;/strong&gt; for the reviewers it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve found about research in general, there are really two high-level
avenues to research. There’s work that focuses on improving industry scale solutions,
research that optimizes the current reality. In general, these types of works will net 
incremental improvement. Intuitively, 
if it’s a problem that really matters many people will be focused on solving that
problem, so the existing solution is probably pretty good. Nevertheless, the
incremental 1\% improvement results in positive impact on 99\% of users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alternative type of research, is the niche but truly novel. This is the type
of work where  a solution improves the current state-of-the-art by many times 
over. The novelty and improvement shows promise in a field either forgotton or
never before seen. With this type of work, there’s two possible implications. 
People realize that this novel area is worth further investigation, and it opens
up a new domain of research, or, it fades into nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the rare occassion, a work will vastly improve the state-of-the-art AND be
impactful at a large scale. These are the “big name works” if you will,
the ones that made people famous and impacted the world. These 
types of works which hit on both levels require a real tenacity for the field, 
in addition to brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the reason why I feel rather detached from the whole situation is that
when I look at my work as well as the work of most of my colleagues, I feel we
slot nicely into either the “real” or “novel”. For example, my interest in Spark
compute engine improvements are very real – changes could quickly make it to 
industry and effect thousands of servers. On the other hand, my colleagues’ work
is novel. They are designing completely new computer architectures to optmize
neural networks. However, the likeliihood that their chip will be fabricated is 
low, and it’s even less likely that the chip design will be widely adopted into
industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, my point isn’t to argue which is better or more interesting – I think that’s
clearly in the eyes of the beholder – but fundamentally, I think we can become
disconnected from importance of our work as researchers. Does what we do really
matter if it’s just 1% improvement or a niche design? Clearly, the answer is yes.
Those 1% improvements stack up from all over the world, and those niche designs
continue to improve until they can no longer be ignored. But simple knowledge
doesn’t override emotional response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think that’s the real crux: the paper rejection pushes me to believe my
incremental improvement is just that. It distances me from believing my work
matters and leaves me feeling blank. While I don’t like ending on such a negative
note, I think I must. Social media promotes only sharing the best aspects of life,
but a big part of reality that is ignored is the lows. This is a low, and that’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Taht</name></author><summary type="html">Today, I found out my submission to the ISPASS conference was rejected. The strange thing about it is, I mostly just feel confused. How should you really feel when a your work is rejected? Discredited? Angry? Confused? For me, I just feel blank.</summary></entry></feed>